It's something that's very important to me.
僕にとっては一生のとても大事なことなんです
I might not even remember my own face soon!
私は自分の顔も忘れてしまいそうなんだぞ！
あの…
Umm...
No! Nooo!
いやぁ～！ いやっ！
Hey!
Yagiri Pharmaceuticals, huh?
「矢霧製薬」ねぇ…
Is this really where those human experiments are being conducted?
ほんとにここなんっすかね～？ 人体実験してるの
That's not Harima Mika...
張間美香じゃない…
You can use as much money however you want.
お金はいくらでも好きなように使えばいいのよ
We'll be together forever.
今の僕らが永遠なんだ
I love you, Celty.
愛してるよ セルティ
All of them are fakes.
みんな みんな 偽物
The world is filled with them.
世の中にあふれてる
They say things like, "I love you," and, "I like you," just to tie others down.
愛してるとか 好きとかいって
束縛するだけ
"Look this way," and, "Stay by my side."
こっちを向いて そばにいて
They just covet and fawn on people.
求めるだけ 甘えるだけ
My love is different.
私の愛は違う
It's a broader, more complete thing.
もっと広くて もっと完全なもの
I know, sis.
分かってるよ 姉さん
Thanks for the money transfer. See you.
振り込み ありがとう
じゃあ また
You want me to get you something to drink?
何か飲み物でも買ってこようか？
See, from that vending machine right over there.
ほら すぐあそこに見える自販だよ
Wait a bit.
待ってて
Whoa.
You're so cute.
かわいい人だな
They still haven't been found?!
まだ見つかってないの？
I'm incredibly sorry...
はっ 申し訳ございません
What in the world was security doing, then?!
一体監視役は何をしていたの？
According to the person in charge,
昨晩の担当が言うには
they were staying in the same hotel, but Seiji suddenly
changed locations in the middle of the night—
このところ同じホテルにお泊まりだったのが
誠二さんが夜中になって急に場所を変えたらしく…
I could still reach him on his cell phone at seven PM.
７時ごろにはまだ携帯も通じていたのよ？
If something were to happen to him...
もし何かあったら…
He promised he wouldn't leave Ikebukuro,
so I believe we'll find him soon.
池袋から離れない約束をしていただいてますから
すぐに見つかるかと
Listen.
いい？ もしあれが警察の目に触れでもしたら
What do you think will happen to us if the police get wind of this?!
私たちはどうなると思う？
Well, that's...
それは…
That's enough.
もういいわ
I can't wait for you guys.
あなたたちを待ってられない
Director...!
主任
I'll be back soon.
すぐに戻ります
To me, it was just a doll.
私にとって あれはただの人形だった
Like one of the expensive, beautiful dolls my
uncle would buy for me on his trips overseas.
伯父が昔よく買ってくれたような
舶来の高価できれいな人形たち
I didn't like dolls when I was young.
幼いころから私は人形が好きではなかった
I assume he wasn't trying to please me,
but just kept sending me things he liked.
たぶん 伯父は私を喜ばせるためではなく
ただ 自分が気に入ったものを贈り続けていたのだと思う
Hey, Seiji, look at this.
ほら 誠二 見てごらん
It's pretty, isn't it?
きれいでしょう？
So, what do you think this one over here is?
さあ こっちは何かな？
What?
何？
It was always utterly silent in that house, and we were always alone.
家の中は静まり返っていて
私と誠二はいつも二人きり
Even before my younger brother was born,
my uncle often had to look after me.
弟が生まれる前から 私は伯父の家に預けられることも多く
I could also enter and leave his study whenever I wanted.
書斎にも自由に出入りしていた
That's...where it was.
あれはそこにあった
My uncle would sometimes gaze at that thing he'd
smuggled in from overseas as if he were in a trance...
外国から密輸入したという
あれを伯父は魅入られたように眺めては
And sometimes he'd even talk to it.
時々話しかけたりもするのだった
It certainly was beautiful.
確かに美しかった 伯父がくれたどんな人形よりも
More so than any doll he'd ever given me.
It didn't seem mysterious or cruel; it seemed
like just its head was a whole creature.
不思議と残酷さは感じられず
まるで 首だけで一つの生き物であるように思えた
But that's all it was to me.
でも私にとってはそれだけ
That's why, when I secretly invited my brother into the study...
だから あの日
弟を書斎にこっそり招き入れたのは
I thought we'd just have some fun.
ただいつもの遊びのつもりだったし
I may have simply wanted to share my secret with him.
秘密を共有したかっただけかもしれない
It's pretty, isn't it?
ねっ きれいでしょう？
That was the beginning of it all...
それがすべての始まり
My one and only regret, which continues to this day.
私のたった一つ… そしていまだに続く後悔
This is the first time we've met, isn't it?
会うのは初めてだよね？
Did that list of illegal immigrants
prove useful to you, Ms. Yagiri Namie?
不法入国者とかのリストは役に立った？ 矢霧波江さん
I'm so happy.
うれしいな～「矢霧製薬」第六研主任に わざわざこんなむさい所までおいでいただけるとは
To have the director of the sixth research
facility come all the way to a place like this...
Please, sit anywhere over there.
どうぞ その辺に適当に掛けて
It's an emergency. Find out where my brother is.
緊急なの 弟の居場所を突き止めて
I'll pay you however much you want.
報酬はいくらでも払います
I haven't been able to contact him since last night.
昨日の夜から連絡が取れない
He should be somewhere in Ikebukuro.
池袋のどこかにいるはず
Not that much time has passed, has it?
まだそんなに時間がたってないじゃない
Why are you so worried?
なんでそんなに心配なの？
He's with a girl; one who has a wound on her neck.
女と一緒にいる
首の周りに傷あとがある女
A girl?
女？
He's at that age, you know.
そういうお年ごろだよ
Get going now!
すぐ動いて！
Wait a second.
ちょっと待ってよ ほかに調べた方がいい大事なことがたくさんあるんじゃないの～？
Aren't there many more important things we should investigate first?
There are rumors going around that your company is
about to be taken over by that foreign company Nebula, right?
おたくの会社 外資系の「ネブラ」って大企業に吸収されちゃうかもって噂だよね？
If that's true, then your position—
そうなったら あんたの立場も…
Mr. Orihara Izaya, I don't have time for idle chitchat.
折原臨也さん おしゃべりしている暇はないの
How unexpected.
意外だな あんたのような優秀な女性が弟愛とはね
That such a capable woman as yourself
would be in love with her younger brother, that is.
What do you know about me?
私の何を知ってるの？
The Yagiri Namie I know is quite a distinguished woman.
オレの知ってる矢霧波江さんは偉い女だよ
I mean, even though it was a family business,
だって いくら同族会社だからって
your father screwed up and had to hand it over
to your uncle, who doesn't do you any favors.
あんたのオヤジさんはヘマやって失墜しちゃったし
現社長の伯父さんは随分クールみたいだしね
So you had to use your own abilities to get the job,
and now you've come this far, despite being so young.
だから 波江さんは自分の力で会社に入って
若くしてここまでの立場になったんだ
And you're also very beautiful.
しかもこんな美人で
You certainly do know me well.
さすが よく知ってるのね
It should be easy for you to search for my brother, then.
あなたなら弟を捜すのもわけないわね
Your brother, huh?
弟ねぇ…
You shouldn't interfere with his business, you know.
あんまり干渉しすぎるのはよくないよ
I'm not interfering!
干渉なんかじゃないわ
I'm the only one who can protect him.
あの子を守るのは私しかいないの
It seems stalkers never do realize what they're doing.
自分だけは気づかないらしいよね ストーカーってさ
They always say they're protecting their—
守ってやってるつもりなんだって
Don't group me together with any stalkers!
私をストーカーなんかと一緒にしないで！
You're scary.
怖っ！
It was just a joke.
冗談じゃな～い
Alright, I'll help you.
よし 協力しましょう
However, we'll do things my way.
ただし オレのやり方でね
Information dealers are different from the police.
警察と情報屋は違うんだから
What rules do you play by...?
どういうルールなのよ
I have a question.
一つ聞くけど
Are you jealous of that girl with the wound on her neck?
その首に傷がある女に焼きもちやいてんの？
Why?
どうして？
There's no way I'd be jealous of her!
あの子に嫉妬するはずない
A chest-burning jealousy that dyes people a rusty red...
私の胸をやく 赤く さび付いた嫉妬は…
Sis...I have...someone I like.
姉さん… オレ 好きな子がいるんだ
I knew Seiji was slowly getting stranger.
誠二の様子がだんだんおかしくなっていったのは分かっていた
He'd go into our uncle's study for no reason at all, then stare at that thing every time he snuck in.
やたらと伯父の書斎に行きたがり
書斎に忍び込んでは あれを夢中で見つめていた
Seiji wasn't in love with a person.
誠二が愛したのは人ではない
It had no soul, or even a body.
心もなく 体さえなく…
I wanted to take Seiji's mind off of it, so I asked my uncle
if I could move it as soon as I entered the company,
誠二の目から遠ざけたくて
入社して すぐ私は伯父に頼み込み
and brought it to the facility as a research subject.
あれを研究対象として社に置いた
That's when it happened.
それからだ 「ネブラ」の接触が始まり
Nebula began contacting us,
and just when I started losing my mind, trying not to
let any information leak, my security card was stolen.
研究を漏らさないよう 私が躍起になっているときに
セキュリティーカードが盗まれた
The card that only I had...
私だけが持っていたカードが
Sis, I might have killed someone.
姉さん… オレ 人を殺しちゃったかもしれないんだ
What should I do?
どうしよう…
And what welled-up in my chest at that moment was neither fear nor anger, but unbounded joy.
そのとき 私の胸に浮かんだのは
恐怖でも 怒りでもなく
果てしない喜びだった
Seiji needed me.
誠二が必要としているのは私
You don't need to worry about anything.
あなたはなんにも心配することはない
Leave everything to your sister.
全部 姉さんに任せて ねっ？
Okay?
Now, about her—not that girl over there...
あの女じゃなくて 彼女のことなんだけど
So you did take her?
やっぱり誠二が連れ出していたのね
It's okay.
大丈夫よ 彼女のことも私に任せなさい
Leave everything about her to me.
It's okay. Really.
大丈夫 絶対…
At that time, I didn't realize there was a
stupid girl named Harima Mika stalking Seiji.
そのころ 誠二に張間美香という頭の悪いストーカー女が
付きまとっていることを私は知らなかったのだ
After she invaded his room without permission and saw "it," Seiji just...
勝手に部屋に侵入され あれを見られた誠二は…
I'll protect you, no matter what.
どんな手を使ってでも 私があなたを守る
Ahh, okay.
ああ～ はいはい
Apparently, you don't have to panic.
そう慌てることもないみたいよ
The police should be picking them up and contacting you shortly.
警察が保護して もうじきあんたに電話が掛かってくるんじゃないかなぁ
I did say "police," but you should be fine.
いや 警察ったって 平気 平気
It's no big deal.
大したことないって たぶん～
I assume.
Don't toy with me!
ふざけないで！
Yes?
はい
Yes, it is.
はい そうですが…
What? What's wrong?
何？ どうしたの？
We're going?
行くの？ でも まだ…
But, we still...
Wait!
待って
I'm happy you love me so much.
君が僕をそんなに愛してくれていて うれしいよ
I love you, too.
僕も君を愛してる ずっと ず～っとね
Forever and ever.
I'm scared.
怖いの…
Of what?
何が？
Please, take me far away...
お願い どこか遠くへ…
I want to be alone with you, too, but where would we go?
僕だって君と二人きりでいたいよ
だけど どこへ…
What's with them?
なんだ？ あれ
A lovers' quarrel?
痴話ゲンカか？
C'mon.
いやっ！ いやぁ～～!!
No!
Stop it!
やめて！ いや… いやぁ～!!
Okay, please calm down.
落ち着いてください オレたちは別に怪しい者じゃないから
We're not bad people or anything.
No! Nooo!
いやっ！ いやぁ～！
Just listen.
話を聞いて…
Let...me...go! Let...me...
Huh?
Let her go!
彼女を放せ！
I'm alright. It doesn't hurt.
オレは大丈夫だから
痛くないし 行って
Just go.
I don't really get it, but you have to chase her, don't you?
なんだか分からないけど 追っかけなきゃやばいんでしょ？
I've always wanted to say this:
一度言ってみたかったんだ
Leave this to me and go on ahead!
「ここはオレに任せて 先に行け」ってな
Wait!
待て！
Uh, so-sorry...
す… すみません 大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
You're...
あっ 君は…
Wait!
待て～！
No, you wait!
いや お前が待て
Let me go!
放せ！ 放せったら！
I said, "Let me go!"
Is she your girlfriend?
あの子 君の彼女？
Yeah, she's my destiny!
そうだ オレの運命の人だ！
Why does she look like that?
彼女なんであんなんなの？
Like I'd know!
知るか！
Whaaaaat's thaaaaat?!
なんだぁ そりゃあ～～!?
Are you saying you don't know your girlfriend?
好きな相手のことを知らないってのはよぉ ちょ～っと無責任じゃねぇのか？
Isn't that a bit irresponsible?
Huh?!
Stuff like that's not important when you love someone!
人を好きになるのに そんなこと関係ない！
Oh?
Then why?
じゃあ なんで
Why's she your destiny?
どういう理由で 運命の人なんだ？
Because I love her!
オレが愛してるからだ ほかに答えなんかない！
There's no other answer!
I can't use another word for it besides "love!"
愛を言葉に置き換えることなんかできやしない！
That's why I...
だから オレは…
きゃあ～ 黒バイ！
The black bike!
...I'm going to act on it!
オレは行動で示す！
I'll protect her!
彼女を守る それだけだ！
That's all it is!
I like you a lot more than Izaya.
臨也よりはずっと気に入った
So I'll leave it at this.
だから これで勘弁してやる！
I'm going to bleed if I pull this out, huh?
抜いたら血が出るよなぁ これ
I'll pull it out after I buy some band-aids.
ばんそうこう買ってから抜こう
No, maybe an instant adhesive would be better?
いや 瞬間接着剤の方がいいか
In other words, your head was walking around attached to another body...
つまり
君の首が体をくっつけて歩いてて
When you caught it, a high schooler interfered...
捕まえたら高校生に邪魔されて
Then another high schooler appeared when you were chasing it...
追いかけたら今度は別の高校生が現れて
And he ran off with it?
君の首を連れ去っていった…
You want me to believe all that?
そんな世まい言を信じろって？
I won't ask you to believe it all.
Well, I do.
信じるよ
But why was Shizuo there?
でも なんでそこに静雄君が？
I'd completely forgotten about that...
すっかり忘れていたけど
臨也からの仕事で公園に待機していたんだ
I was waiting in the park while on a job from Izaya,
when Shizuo happened to pass by, so we started talking...
そこに静雄が通りかかって ちょっと話を
Anyway, I got a message afterward saying the job was canceled, so it's okay.
結局その仕事はドタキャンになったって あとから連絡が入ったから いいんだ
Orihara, huh?
折原君か…
Anyway, I wanted to talk to you...
So, you're still confused, huh?
まだ混乱中だね
I'll listen to whatever you have to say.
話相手なら いくらでもするよ
Why is my head on someone else's body?!
そもそも なんで私の首に私以外の体があるんだ!?
I'm in the dark, seeing as I didn't witness
the events, but if I could venture a guess...
まあ 実際に見ていない僕が何を言っても白河夜船だが
推測でもよければ
What if...
例えば… 体格の合いそうな女の子を見つけて
It found a girl who looked like she had your build and attached itself to her.
適当に首をすげ替えたんじゃないかな
That's horrifying...
おぞましいことを
It could've found a newly dead corpse.
出来たてホヤホヤの死体があったとか
Stop that!
But...no...
でも そ… そんなこと…
It couldn't have...
What I did wasn't wrong...
私がしたことは間違ってなかったはずだ
Creating that girl with the body from that incident...For Seiji's sake...
あの事件の後
誠二のためにあの子をつくり出したことは…
I have to go.
行かなきゃ
It's okay.
大丈夫よ もう大丈夫だから
Everything's okay.
She...
彼女が…
It was scary, wasn't it?
怖かったわね
She...
But nothing went wrong, did it?
でも何も問題なかったじゃない
My love never faltered, even when she ran away and met up with Seiji.
あの子がここを逃げ出して 誠二と一緒になったときも
私の愛は何も揺るがなかった
Seiji's love uses my love for him as a stepping-stone.
私の愛を踏み台にして誠二の愛があり
He knows that, and I know that he knows.
誠二はそれを知っていて
知っていることを私も知っている
Everything's twisted, but still...
何もかも歪んでいて それでも…
Damn, that was a Raira Academy uniform.
くそっ 来良学園の制服…
Who was he?
誰だ？ あいつ
I know, so just leave it to me.
分かってるから 任せて
Anyway, we've got to find a girl from Raira.
ともかく来良の子を見つけ出す
Then all I can do is meet my head and talk with it.
それから首と会って話すしかない
You mean the head that could only scream when it saw you?
君を見て悲鳴しか上げなかった首と？
What're you going to do about a head that's living as a complete person?
一人の人間として生きているらしい首をどうしようっていうの？
Are you telling me you'd separate it from its body for your own sake?
君のためにその首を体から切り離すとでもいうのかい？
Celty...
セルティ
I don't want to admit...
認めたくないんだ
That I've lost my head and my memories...
私の首と私の記憶は失われたと
That all my efforts these past twenty years have been in vain...
自分のしてきた事が この２０年間が全て無駄だったなんて
They haven't been in vain.
無駄なんかじゃないさ
I'll get her back for you.
絶対に彼女を取り戻してみせるから
Just wait here.
あなたはここで待ってて
Oh yeah, where's your cell phone?
あっ ねえ 携帯は？ 落としたの？
Did you lose it?
I don't know.
分からない
It wasn't there, even though I put it in my bag.
なかった かばんにしまったのに
Eh?
She...needs me.
彼女はオレがいなくちゃダメなんだ
We have to be alone.
二人きりじゃなくちゃ
Really? I guess so...
そう… そうなのね
It's alright. Leave everything to your big sister.
いいのよ 全部 姉さんに任せて
What nerve!
なんてずうずうしい
Dolls should act like dolls and do as they're told.
人形は人形らしくおとなしくしていればよかったのだ
And not interfere with my love.
私の愛を邪魔せずに
I've decided...
決めた もう後悔だけはしたくない
I don't want to regret anything else...
Ever again.
二度と…
Listen.
いい？ 下の連中全員にすぐ連絡を回して
Circulate a message to all our underlings.
I don't care whether she dies or not.
生死は問わないわ
Depending on the circumstances, dispose of her on the spot.
場合によってはそのまま処理してしまいなさい！
I see.
なるほど～ 皆さんお忙しい
Everyone's busy.
I can't wait!
楽しみだなぁ 楽しみだなぁ 楽しみだなぁ！
I can't wait!!
I can't wait!!!
There are so, so, so many things even I don't know in this town that continually appear and disappear!
この街は情報屋のオレでも知らないことがまだまだまだあふれ
生まれ消えていく
That's why I can't leave a city where so many people gather!
これだから人間の集まる街は離れられない
人 ラブ！
People love!
I like people!
オレは人間が好きだ！ 愛してる！
I love them!
That's why...
だからこそ！
People should love me as well.
人間の方もオレを愛するべきだよねぇ
Thank you.
ありがとう
Do you feel any calmer?
少しは落ち着いた？
Can you answer questions?
質問に答えられる？
You said you didn't remember anything, right?
なんにも覚えてないって 言ったよね？
In other words, that means...umm...you have amnesia?
つまり それは… え～っと 記憶喪失ってこと？
I'll say it again, but I think you should go to the police or a hospital...
う～んと… もう一度言うけど
警察とか病院に行った方が…
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい
ごめんなさい ごめんなさい！
No, it's okay.
いや いいの いいの 謝らないで
Please don't apologize.
I have to go...
行かなきゃ… あの人が邪魔する前に
Before she interferes...
Forever and ever—
ずっと ずっと…
I have to go.
行かなきゃ…
Seiji...
誠二…
誠二さん…
I love you.
あなたを愛してる
制作：lastzzz 安静の云 akira アキラ
Err...
え～っと 首なしライダーに折原臨也
The headless rider, Orihara Izaya, and the
girl with the wounded neck appeared again...
首に傷のある女の子がまた現れて
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs/
And to top it all off, a guy from the next class over is in The Dollars!
おまけに隣のクラスの彼はダラーズで…
Next Time: The First and Only.
I had a dream where I was leading an abnormal life, yet...
普通じゃない生活を夢見てた けど…